Harshveer Singh Dhaliwal, Chartered Accountant

+91 9330000099 ca.hvsdhaliwal@gmail.com

|linkedin.com/in/harshveer-dhaliwal-97a974262

Professional Summary

Chartered Accountant with over 3 years of experience with broad and in-depth knowledge of accounting, proficient financial and risk analysis, audit co-ordination & review of books of accounts and tax analysis. Extensively used Microsoft Excel for calculation and data validation, prepared reports and statements for various regulatory filings. Attention to detail and quality in business operations & strategic planning. Track record of positive academic performance with superior numerical and analytical skills along with exceptional problem solving and communication skills.

Work Experience

January 2021 - September 2022
IDS Infotech Ltd.

Finance & Accounts

- Assisted with accounts review and preparation of financial statements.
- Verified financial journals for clarity and completion under supervisor direction.
- Examined financial risks and benefits by looking daily at cash flows, fund flows, debt coverage and rates of return.
- Engaged in finalization of balance sheet of IDS infotech (IT Industry).
- GST returns and filing of various applicable returns with GST Dept.
- Review of Transfer Pricing study reports under supervision.
- Prepared reconciliations for mismatches and attested same in system keeping necessary substantiation in record for process of Payroll processing for employees.
- Various documentations and submission in assessment of income tax cases of IDS Infotech ltd.
- Review of overseas subsidiary company financial statements.
- Secretarial compliances like Annual Returns, Minutes Preparation, Board Resolutions, MIS of the company etc.

• January 2018 - April 2020

Deviyal K & Co.

Article Trainee

- Assisted with preparation of financial statements and review of books of accounts to obtain reasonable assurance.
- Reconciliation of TDS receivable with 26AS.
- Compiled general ledger entries on schedule with 100% accuracy.
- Filing and preparation of Income tax returns and advance tax working for individuals and companies.
- Reconciled statements to resolve discrepancies.
- Maintained records and files to furnish reliable documentation.
- Conducted technical and analytical reviews of tax returns to check for accuracy and deductions.

April 2017 - January 2018

Khurana Sharma & Co.

Article Trainee

- Exposure to statutory audit of firm in manufacturing industry Kamal hi-tech.
- Assisted in preparation of financial reports for Medical & healthcare giant PGI-Chd.
- Prepared consolidated financial statements for Indian head office of company which had operations in UK and converted foreign branch financials as per I-GAAP.
- Completed audit papers by thoroughly documenting audit and findings.
- Used accounting software to issue tax returns and prepare consolidated reports.
- TDS review and computation of TDS liability of clients on monthly basis along with revision of TDS returns.

Education:

• 2022

CA Final Group 2 - Nov'22 (230/400 = 57.5%)

• 2021

CA Final Group 1 - Dec'21 (217/400 = 54.25%)

• 2018

CA IPCC (414/700=59.14%)

• 2017

B.Com. – GGDSD College, Panjab University

• 2014

Class XII – Bhavan Vidyalaya (466/500=93.2%)

2012

Class X – St. Anne's Convent School (9.2 CGPA)

Academic Certifications:

ICAI

- Advanced Integrated course on Information Technology & soft skills.
- 2. 15 Day course on management and communication skills (MCS)
- 3. Underwent 'Information Technology Training Course 'and cleared relevant test.

Skills:

- Business tools: MS Office suite (Word, Excel, Excel Macros, PowerPoint), Google docs, MS Visio.
- Excellent Communication Skills.
- Ability to drive data-driven information.
- Diverse knowledge of accounting concepts.

Language:

English Panjabi Hindi

Interests:

Gaming Football